[
  {
    "question": "In which decade did artists start to think of artworks as an ecosystem?",
    "a": "1980s",
    "b": "1950s",
    "c": "1940s",
    "d": "1920s",
    "e": "1960s",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ecosystems came to be understood through robust system theories in the period after",
    "a": "Vietnam War",
    "b": "Civil War",
    "c": "World War II",
    "d": "Korean War",
    "e": "World War I",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who coined the term “System Esthetics” in 1968?",
    "a": "Jack Burnham",
    "b": "Thomas Cole",
    "c": "John Constable",
    "d": "Helen Harrison",
    "e": "Edward Burtynsky",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Helen and Newton Harrison live from 1957 to 1960?",
    "a": "Milan",
    "b": "Naples",
    "c": "Rome",
    "d": "Florence",
    "e": "Venice",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What substance did the Harrisons NOT use in Making Earth?",
    "a": "peat moss",
    "b": "sand",
    "c": "cow manure",
    "d": "leaf material",
    "e": "sewage sludge",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "At which museum was Shrimp Farm staged?",
    "a": "The Broad",
    "b": "Hammer Museum",
    "c": "The Getty Center",
    "d": "LACMA",
    "e": "MOCA",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "At which exhibition was Shrimp Farm performed?",
    "a": "Ecological Displays",
    "b": "Earthworks",
    "c": "Innovative Art",
    "d": "Nature in Art",
    "e": "Arts and Technology",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many pounds of salt water did the Harrisons use for Notations of the Ecosystem of the Western Salt Works?",
    "a": "five",
    "b": "seven",
    "c": "two",
    "d": "four",
    "e": "eight",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do the “Survival” works highlight interrelations among organisms and livable climate conditions?",
    "a": "depicting abstract concepts of ecological balance",
    "b": "examining the role of technology in ecological preservation",
    "c": "creating highly specific and localized living conditions",
    "d": "displaying the consequences of organism displacement",
    "e": "simulating the effects of climate change across different habitats",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What fallacy did the “Survival” works demonstrate?",
    "a": "They were too manipulated to reflect true nature.",
    "b": "They focused solely on individual organisms.",
    "c": "They were too temporary to accurately depict any ecosystem.",
    "d": "They were overly complicated and scientific.",
    "e": "They disrupted the natural behaviors and habitats of organisms.",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organism’s scientific name is Scylla serrata?",
    "a": "spider crab",
    "b": "horseshoe crab",
    "c": "mud crab",
    "d": "blue crab",
    "e": "king crab",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "How was The Lagoon Cycle different from previous “Survival” works?",
    "a": "It was not limited to a predetermined period of time.",
    "b": "It included an environment with temperature controls.",
    "c": "It did not mimic a previous ecosystem.",
    "d": "It was available to the public for a fee.",
    "e": "It explored a marine environment.",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did the Harrisons simulate monsoon conditions in The Lagoon Cycle?",
    "a": "decreasing salinity and increasing food",
    "b": "increasing salinity and decreasing light",
    "c": "decreasing food and decreasing temperature",
    "d": "increasing food and decreasing temperature",
    "e": "increasing light and increasing food",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many cycles did The Lagoon Cycle experimentations contain?",
    "a": "four",
    "b": "five",
    "c": "eight",
    "d": "six",
    "e": "seven",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which description BEST describes the text on The Lagoon Cycle?",
    "a": "a narration of the life cycle of a crab",
    "b": "a story of a crab during monsoon season",
    "c": "a description of the life cycle of a crab",
    "d": "a dialogue between a crab and a fish",
    "e": "a lab report about an experiment about crab reproduction",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Hans Haacke born?",
    "a": "Germany",
    "b": "Switzerland",
    "c": "Austria",
    "d": "Belgium",
    "e": "Denmark",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which European city was the “Zero Group” based?",
    "a": "Frankfurt",
    "b": "Innsbruck",
    "c": "Graz",
    "d": "Cologne",
    "e": "Düsseldorf",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kinetic Art pieces are set apart from more traditional sculpture by their",
    "a": "far larger scale",
    "b": "inclusion of mechanical parts",
    "c": "integration with the surrounding environment",
    "d": "dramatic, emotional composition",
    "e": "high degree of impractical abstraction",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What material did Haacke use in the clean water tank in Rhine Water Purification Plant?",
    "a": "aluminum",
    "b": "extruded plastic",
    "c": "glass",
    "d": "plexiglass",
    "e": "steel",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What biological element was included in Rhine Water Purification Plant?",
    "a": "a moss garden fed by the clean water",
    "b": "a fish in the clean water tank",
    "c": "a tree incorporated into the sculptural construction",
    "d": "ducks in the storage pond",
    "e": "bacterial colonies in the purification process",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which material was used for the filters in Rhine Water Purification Plant?",
    "a": "mesh",
    "b": "ash",
    "c": "gravel",
    "d": "plastic",
    "e": "sand",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following works did Hans Haacke create first?",
    "a": "Condensation Cube",
    "b": "Rhine Water Purification Plant",
    "c": "MoMA Poll",
    "d": "Wave",
    "e": "Grass Grows",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What name did Jack Burnham use to describe the series of works which included Wave?",
    "a": "Wave Works",
    "b": "Tide Pieces",
    "c": "Ebb and Flow Art",
    "d": "Flowing Art",
    "e": "Wind and Water Works",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "At which university was Hans Haacke’s work displayed during the spring of 1969?",
    "a": "Carnegie Mellon",
    "b": "Brown",
    "c": "Colombia",
    "d": "Cornell",
    "e": "Harvard",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of unexpected weather thwarted the construction of Hans Haacke’s Ice Rope?",
    "a": "a hailstorm",
    "b": "a heat wave",
    "c": "a blizzard",
    "d": "a severe thunderstorm",
    "e": "a flash flood",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "What theme did Grass Grows seek to explore?",
    "a": "the persistence of nature",
    "b": "the virtue of patience",
    "c": "the cycle of life and death",
    "d": "the beauty of the mundane",
    "e": "human degradation of the environment",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which interactive element did MoMA Poll include?",
    "a": "audience voting",
    "b": "tactile mineral elements",
    "c": "a camera photographing audience reaction",
    "d": "informational tablet",
    "e": "production of drinking water",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "How are MoMA Poll and Shapolsky similar?",
    "a": "Both were censored prior to their debut.",
    "b": "Both are photograph series.",
    "c": "Both involved themes of war.",
    "d": "Both debuted at the Guggenheim Museum.",
    "e": "Both are institutional critique works.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which museum notoriously censored and removed some of Hans Haacke’s work?",
    "a": "The Metropolitan Museum of Art",
    "b": "Krefeld Art Museum",
    "c": "The Haus Lange",
    "d": "The Guggenheim Museum",
    "e": "The Louvre",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company did Hans Haacke MOST directly connect to the pollution of the Rhine?",
    "a": "Henkel AG",
    "b": "Linde PLC",
    "c": "The Auto Group",
    "d": "Dow Chemicals",
    "e": "The Bayer Group",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  }
]